# Andrei Popikov

Software Engineer

Voronezh, Russia

☑ agpopikov@gmail.com
③ agpopikov.info
in agpopikov
② agpopikov



I am a software engineer with 10+ years of experience specializing in Java and Kotlin development (actively using Kotlin since 1.2). I have extensive experience working with frameworks & libraries such as Spring, Hibernate, jOOQ, testcontainers and many others. Additionally, I have good leadership & communication skills and I'm always trying to understand business needs.

## Main skills

Kotlin, Java, Spring Framework (Boot, Security, Cloud), jOOQ, Flyway, PostgreSQL, Apache Cassandra, Clickhouse, Kafka, testcontainers, API design (Swagger / OpenAPI standards), Angular, TypeScript, sofware architecture, application performance analysis (async-profiler, YourKit), cloud technologies (mostly AWS) including hybrid solutions, building & leading software engineering teams, agile methodologies.

# Experience

2020 – present

#### Lead Software Engineer, Madtest

- Joined Madtest at an early stage, responsible for backend development and infrastructure.
- Developed many parts of existing solution including core logic, auth, payments, etc; using Kotlin as the main language alongside Spring Framework, with PostgreSQL and Clickhouse for data storage.
- Implemented a hybrid cloud infrastructure that leverages AWS and onpremise servers, significantly reducing operational costs while ensuring high availability.

2021 – 2023 December August

#### **Lead Software Engineer**, *Technolab (part-time)*

- Joined as a lead engineer to assist in performance optimizations and architectural improvements for one of the largest ticket-selling platforms in a region.
- Led efforts in building and onboarding a new development team to enhance the platform's scalability and reliability.
- Worked on existing services written in Java (with Spring, Hibernate), worked closely with DevOps team to improve overall maintainability.

2020 - 2021

August

Sr. Java Developer, *lconsoft* 

- O Developed new and maintained existing services written in Java (JHipsterbased projects).
- O Assisted in the adoption and integration of the Camunda BPMN platform to make process management more flexible & observable.

2015 - 2019February December

### Lead Software Engineer, Inleksys, Voronezh

- O Built & lead development team (around 10 devs).
- Worked on development of web applications using technologies such as Java, Kotlin, Spring, PostgreSQL, Redis, Kafka, TypeScript, Angular.
- Improved CI/CD processes, introduced & standardized peer-code reviews practice among different teams.
- Participated in development of prototypes and proof-of-concept solutions for different customers (IoT projects, mobile applications based on the Flutter platform).
- O Actively participated in the company's HR processes:
  - Participated in technical interviews, worked on improving hiring processes.
  - Organized and led several courses on the basics of Java and web development for students.

2014 - 2015February January

### **Software Engineer**, *Vistar*, Voronezh

- O Developed web services using Java, Spring, MyBatis for real time public transportation monitoring system.
- O Developed several mobile application prototypes using Apache Cordova (Angular.js / jQuery).

# Languages

Russian native

English fluent

German beginner (A2)

## Education

#### 2012–2016 **Voronezh State University**;

Studied computer science @ Faculty of Computer Science; Programming and Information Technologies Department;

## Hobbies & interests

IoT devices development (mostly STM32/ESP32 based). I have a bit of experience working with DSP/FPGA (mostly Xilinx-based FPGA) & designing basic circuits.